Finding Aid for Michigan Politicians Portraits collection.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Politicians Portraits collection 1885-1982
Bentley Historical Library
0.4 linear feet
2014044 Aa 2
Collection of 26 portraits of Michigan governors, lieutenant governors and senators, scattered between 1885-1982. All portraits except two were autographed by politicians pictured to Charles A. Sink, Michigan Republican politician.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Collection generated from various sources over an extended period of time.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Michigan Territory, which came under American rule in 1805, was incorporated as the 26th state on January 26, 1837. Since its founding, Michigan has had 48 governors and 40 state senators. The portraits of a small number of these political leaders are included in this collection.
Most photos in the collection were autographed to Charles A. Sink, a Republican politician. Sink served twice as a Republican member of the Michigan House of Representatives (1919-1920 and 1925-1926) and three times in the Michigan Senate, taking office from 1921-1922, 1927-1927, and 1929-1930. He was director of both the University of Michigan Musical Society (1927-1968) and the University of Michigan School of Music (1927-1940).
Portrait collection of Michigan politicians spanning the years 1885-1982, with most photos from the period 1927-1982. Collection consists of two folders: "Governors" which contains 19 photographs, and "Senators", which contains 7 photographs. All dates listed correspond to the terms served by each politician.
Subjects:
Alger, R. A. (Russell Alexander), 1836-1907.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.; Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.; Ferguson, Homer, 1888-1982.; Fitzgerals, Frank D. (Frank Dwight), 1885-1939.; Governors--Michigan.; Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Griffin, Robert P. (Robert Paul), 1923-; Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Alexander Joseph), 1873-1953.; Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Kelly, Harry F. (Harry Francis), 1895-1971.; McNamara, Pat, 1894-1966.; Milliken, William G., 1922-; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), 1860-1949.; Pingree, Hazen S., 1840-1901.; Potter, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1916-1979.; Romney, George W., 1907-1995.; Sigler, Kim, 1894-; Swainson, John B. (John Burley), 1925-1994.; Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.; Van Wagoner, Murray.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Legislators--Michigan.; Politicians--Michigan.
Contributors:
Sink, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1879-1972.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Portraits.
- Michigan Politicians Portraits collection
  - Governors
    - Alger, Russell A., 1885-1887 (Box 1)
    - Brucker, Wilber M., 1931-1933 (Box 1)
    - Comstock, William A., 1933-1935 (Box 1)
    - Dickinson, Luren D., 1915-1921, 1927-1933, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Fitzgerald, Frank D., January-March 1939 (Box 1)
    - Green, Fred W., 1927-1931 (Box 1)
    - Groesbeck, Alexander J., 1921-1927, 2 photographs (Box 1)
    - Kelly, Harry F., 1943-1947, 2 photographs (Box 1)
    - Milliken, William G., 1965-1969 (Box 1)
    - Murphy, Frank, 1937-1939 (Box 1)
    - Osborn, Chase S., 1911-1913 (Box 1)
    - Pingree, Hazen S., 1897-1901 (Box 1)
    - Romney, George, 1963-1969 (Box 1)
    - Sigler, Kim, 1947-1949 (Box 1)
    - Swainson, John B., 1961-1963 (Box 1)
    - Van Wagoner, Murray D., 1941-1943 (Box 1)
    - Williams, G. Mennen, 1949-1961 (Box 1)
  - Senators
    - Ferguson, Homer, 1943-1955 (Box 1)
    - Griffin, Robert P., 1966-1979 (Box 1)
    - Hart, Philip A., 1959-1976 (Box 1)
    - McNamara, Patrick V., 1955-1966 (Box 1)
    - Potter, Charles E., 1952-1959 (Box 1)
    - Townsend, Charles Elroy, 1911-1923 (Box 1)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1928-1951 (Box 1)